[SPEAKER_01]: Can you tell how you broke into baseball, where and when, in the minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_00]: You mean through, I mean not Semapro?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, yeah, even Semapro.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe they come over here to look me over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me just where you grew up and how.
[SPEAKER_00]: I grew up in City South Bend right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was born on Cherry Street over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm raised on Chestnut over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, after I married and played ball, I lived in different places, but my folks lived here since 1916, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then after they died, I inherited the home.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was my oldest brother that you saw now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's 77.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we inherited the home.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we're here ever since 19, when I quit playing ball in 43.
[SPEAKER_00]: So there's no place like home, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, the neighborhood kind of deteriorated a little bit, but I mean, other than that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where did your parents move here?
[SPEAKER_00]: To America?
[SPEAKER_00]: They came here in 1892, but they met here.
[SPEAKER_00]: They married in 1895, and my oldest brother was born in 1897.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right there on Cherry Street.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were born in 1907?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was born in 1907, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was born ten years later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, where did they come from in Poland?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they come from Poland, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have to think of the town.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall the name of the little village just now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although Mother, she was a maid, but from the German side.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, Poland was divided between half Russian and half Polish.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were from the German side of Poland.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was like a housemaid, I guess, in Berlin apartments, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: or rich people had them for apartments.
[SPEAKER_00]: Daddy, he skipped just before Kaiser got into the Army.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he was 18, I guess, or 19 when he skipped.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he had a brother here in Milwaukee already that probably brought him in, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And just before Hitler, I mean, just before Kaiser was going to get him into service, which was forced then, you know, they just got him working.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took off over here because his brother was over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got the name of the little town now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Slupce, yeah, the name of the town was Slupce.
[SPEAKER_00]: Slupce?
[SPEAKER_00]: Slupce, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's in the eastern, well, the eastern part of Poland, I mean the western part of Poland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you speak Polish at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes I do, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Polish school for eight years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had Polish catechism, Polish history, Polish religion.
[SPEAKER_01]: Speak it and write it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes sir, St. Henry's Parish right over here, about 15 minute walk from here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Still belong to the same parish.
[SPEAKER_00]: After the war, I had some of my cousins write, that's after the First World War, write over here, you know, I was about 12, 13 years old, but this must be the 20s, and they wrote in German, you know, and nobody could bother, forgot the German, you know, bother, they could probably speak it, but they couldn't read it or write it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went and got it interpreted, you know, and I wrote them back in Polish, you know, and they wrote back and says, how can somebody born in this country
[SPEAKER_00]: learned to write so well in Polish, and you know, I said, well, I learned it in school.
[SPEAKER_00]: I learned my ABCs in English and Polish more.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I can speak both languages.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a few words that you can't, you don't use too often, you probably can't recall, you know, because it's like somebody asked me the other day, how do you say plumber in Polish?
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, if he's in Poland, there was no plumbers in Poland, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we looked it up, the Polish book, and it's like a, like a Polish, English version of it, but spelled different, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then Olownik is one of them, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: But you don't use that kind of language around here, you know, because you don't have the use for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever get back to Poland?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I never went to Poland.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was born here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never went back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never had no desire.
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked my daddy why he never went back to Poland.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, dad, if I, son, he says, the reason I left Poland, because there was nothing there for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just that they were like sharecroppers, more or less, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, there was no future for me there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I took off.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I just never had no desire to go back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Under the conditions they had then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, maybe a little better now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those days they didn't have nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the lords, you know, the landlords, or what do you want to call them, sharecroppers, all they were.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they just got a pig and a cow and just made a living, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: What did your baseball skills teach you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Right over here, right over here in the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't have nothing else to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't have no bicycles.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't have no roller skates.
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't have nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't afford it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So there's a lot of open fields over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played ball in the morning and the afternoons and evenings.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's all there was to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing else to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Naughty kids, what'd they do?
[SPEAKER_00]: They got an automobile, they got bicycles.
[SPEAKER_00]: And trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd get in trouble, that's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's all we had to do was play.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, some of them developed more than others, but I mean, at least each neighborhood had a team, more or less.
[SPEAKER_00]: One gang would play the other, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have an early desire to make the big leagues?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, after I got the summer Pro Bowl, yes, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did this happen?
[SPEAKER_00]: This was when I was about 15, 16 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 16 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just went through the eighth grade.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't go to high school because the need at home, you know, for money at home.
[SPEAKER_00]: After all, there was eight of us children.
[SPEAKER_00]: Daddy only working, there were two brothers working, they were married.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when I was 16 years old, I started working.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I was playing ball for student leaguers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played a lot of semi-pro then, because all around South Bend, town was 30, 40, 50 miles away.
[SPEAKER_00]: Every one of them had a team, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now they don't, but I mean, in them days they did.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd jump in the car and ride up gravel roads, you know, half an hour, an hour, and played ball and came back, maybe made yourself a $5 bill, and that was your spending money.
[SPEAKER_00]: You didn't get no spending money out of your paycheck.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then later on, we played exhibition games against Philadelphia, Ty Cobb, when Ty Cobb was at Philadelphia in 1927, 28, in that area.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, County Mack Motors team down here, my old manager, Jimmy Dykes.
[SPEAKER_00]: play an exhibition game right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd seen Babe Ruth previous to that, where Babe Ruth was a Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played exhibition games after World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was my desire.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had pretty good luck stroking the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just hit the ball pretty good, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played the outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't want to play the infield.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was too many bad hops in the infield on these fields over here, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I hit the ball real good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And somebody in Indianapolis got nosy about it, or found out about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: come down here and look me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the year previous to that, we had a man over here, he was like a scout, more or less, from Mississauga.
[SPEAKER_00]: He signed me up to a contract for the St. Louis Cards to send me to Danville in the 3I League.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 27, I believe it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, in 28, because I got married in 28, and I was supposed to go in 29, spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't, my wife didn't want me to go because the baby was coming up, and she said, I'd rather have you around, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I did a report spring training in 1929 to Danville.
[SPEAKER_00]: So June 1921, baby was born.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this man come here from Indianapolis, an Indianapolis scout, to watch me play against Donnie Bush's Pittsburgh Pirates.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Donnie Bush comes in, and he says, Ali Bama?
[SPEAKER_00]: Who's Ali Bama?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's in uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, we can't play him.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I was turned into Judge Landis, and I was on the blacklist.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I was on the blacklist, because I had to report to the St. Louis Cardinals firing team in Danville.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never gave it a thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know nothing about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just did a report that my wife didn't want me to go, so I didn't go.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the following day, I said, well, I'm going to go to my wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked my wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: We watched the ball game together sitting in the grandstand.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where he found me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Instead of playing, I was sitting in the grandstand watching the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And after the game, we drove to my home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we asked my wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my wife, she consented.
[SPEAKER_00]: She says, OK.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the following day, 6 o'clock in the morning, I take off.
[SPEAKER_00]: We go to Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I tried out over there, and they signed me to a contract over there, but I had to get my release from Danville.
[SPEAKER_00]: What they paid for it, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: They must have paid something.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I was good enough to start in AA Ball, they must have given some money.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how much.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was none of my business.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get any of it myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they signed me to a contract, so I stayed with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: What year was this?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1929.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1929, you signed with Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Indianapolis Indians.
[SPEAKER_01]: First professional contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: First professional.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the first contract I signed was with Danville, but I didn't report.
[SPEAKER_00]: but I was still tied down to the professional ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I finished 29 with the Indianapolis as an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: And 30, somebody got hurt in Quincy, Illinois, their farm team in May, I guess, or something like that, about a month after the season started.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was sent down there, and they made an infielder out of me on there, because the second baseman, a shortstop, got hurt.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the second baseman went to play short, and they made the second baseman out of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had some pretty good years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Benson Greenberg was playing with
[SPEAKER_00]: with Evansville.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Walker brothers were playing with Evansville, Gerald Walker and Hubby Walker.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Tommy Bridges was doing the pitching for them then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, it was all coming up to, you know, coming through.
[SPEAKER_00]: Class B ball, that was, the Three Eyed League was class B ball then.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, now they don't have those kind of leagues anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: You used to have them all the way down to D ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where you learned your fundamentals from there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if it was good enough, you moved up every year, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now they don't have it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess they go out of college now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But them days, now if you don't go to college, I don't think there's much of a chance for you to get into professional baseball, unless you're an exception.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because there are more minors for you to come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that was 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I stayed there in 30 and 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a good year in 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit 340-something, and the St. Louis Browns bought me.
[SPEAKER_00]: So in 33, they sent me to San Antonio, Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was Wichita Falls, Texas, rather.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was Texas league then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And from there,
[SPEAKER_00]: Wichita Falls pulled out and went to Longview, Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was when they hit oil.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was one of the largest oil fields in America at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Shreveport pulled out, and they went to Tyler, and Wichita Falls pulled out, and they went to Longview.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was towns about 12,000, but nothing but oil fields, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they really supported us.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit the first home run in Tyler in a new ballpark, and they started passing the hammer on, but they had an opposing team, and they quit.
[SPEAKER_00]: quit passing around.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was the visiting team.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was from Longview.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was about maybe 15, 20 miles apart is all.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I lost out on passing ahead because I was from the opposing team.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we finished up in Longview.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then that was 1934 I got called up.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the St. Louis Bonds and the Hornsman, 1934, 1935, and 1936.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went up with Harlan Clift.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and I were roommates.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and I went up from- From Walla Walla.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: From Yakima.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yakima, Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was from Yakima, Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to walk up and down Broadway and they had them cherries from there, they had them apples from there, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Yakima Valley.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, my God.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he sent me a bushel of apples one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: It cost me more for the freight than the apples were worth.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about 2,500 miles of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they were delicious, boy, they were real good.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was 36.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then 36 and 37, I went back to San Antonio.
[SPEAKER_00]: St. Louis, Brownsville, back to San Antonio.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had a good year there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And St. Paul bought me in 38.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to 38.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when Mr. Schultz, I was in penis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you know that?
[SPEAKER_00]: You were what?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in penis, Mr. Schultz.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in penis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Want to stop that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll show you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Stop it, Gene, so we can see this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just saw a man over here in the tavern the other day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's from Phoenix, Arizona, he said he saw it, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: So he and I talked for about 20 minutes, like I say, and he was telling me that he was 16 years old, and I was his hero.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was having a good year, see, I had a real good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, in fact, I was chosen the most valuable player.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whitlow Wyatt and I was the most valuable players.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1938.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1938, in the American Association?
[SPEAKER_00]: American Association, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wonderful.
[SPEAKER_00]: He talks about 20 minutes that he was talking about.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he still has my little autograph, Bat, my little autograph on it, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said he can still remember the night that he bought the Bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: He still did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had quite a chat.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, if I ever, I got 12 grandchildren, and each one got a separate character, you know, as souvenirs, signed by him, and you couldn't get them away from them for $1,000 apiece.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 38.
[SPEAKER_00]: Are we still on?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 38.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I had a good year and the White Sox bought me.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went to the White Sox in 39 and I played with the White Sox in 39 and I hit, I think it was 251, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it didn't seem like it was good enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they sent me back to St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was in St. Paul in 40 and 41 and in 42 they sold me to, uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: San Francisco, Pacific Coast League.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played for Lefty O'Doul over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was a real good league.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played night ball and on Sundays you'd play doubleheaders, you wouldn't play on Monday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, you'd travel from Seattle all the way down to San Diego and it was all down the coast and you had an off day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I, that was during the war, my family wouldn't go out there because they thought the Japs had the coast already, although they didn't, but I was there one time on some oil field outside of Los Angeles there somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: And
[SPEAKER_00]: I told him I wouldn't come back.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I can't recall the guy's name.
[SPEAKER_00]: He owned the Giants before the Giants went to San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, you know, the Giants in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't think of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stoneman, was it Stoneman?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he owned San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was their farm team.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, Ollie, he says, you go home for a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, you think that would break the monotony?
[SPEAKER_00]: And my boy was about two years old then.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I think it would.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he paid the expenses, he paid my wages.
[SPEAKER_00]: Instead of going home for a week, I was here for two weeks, right during the July season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, you know, ballplayers, I was, at that time, I was, oh, 34, 35, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you're too old to go to the service, because I had three children.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the kids were, you know, now they were grabbing them into service.
[SPEAKER_00]: There wasn't too many kids coming up.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they were kind of short for ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they were trying to hang out here, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got a two weeks vacation, which was very unusual.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they said, did you go home?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did go home.
[SPEAKER_00]: I met them after two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the following year, I said, I'm not coming back because I don't want to go live a life like I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they traded me off to the Buffalo International League.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played there for Greg Millevie, the old White Sox shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the manager down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played, well, it was Syracuse, Buffalo, Rochester, Montreal, and so was Toronto was in it too.
[SPEAKER_00]: So first time I played ball in Montreal, I was leadoff man, and they start announcing the lineups, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they called my name, and he says, Ali Bima.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, Dujumbu, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, my God, I got out of the batter's box.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, what did he say?
[SPEAKER_00]: The catcher said, well, it's second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he says, I says, what's the rest of the lineup?
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, well, Premier Bou is first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dujumbu is second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harikou is the shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: Trawajumbu is the third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the Czar, the Czar is the pitcher, and the rest of that is the catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Arbic was the umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall the outfielder no more because that's too long ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I can remember the umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like to, I like to dig when, when I heard them announcing those different lineups.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think they still do it in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean they announce in French, in English.
[SPEAKER_00]: So after, I guess they do, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So after, I was the 43, I was the 43 and I says, I says to the wife, I think I'm gonna give it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was during the war, you know, the war was still going on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I don't know if I can get a job over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to travel around.
[SPEAKER_00]: They couldn't come see me.
[SPEAKER_00]: When they did come see me, you're supposed to take a 10 o'clock train, you know, I was home for two weeks, there's only 400 and something miles from South Bend, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're supposed to take a 10 o'clock train going home, you couldn't get on, full of soldiers.
[SPEAKER_00]: 12 o'clock train full of soldiers, 2 o'clock in the morning before her and the baby would get on to come home, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was a dog's life too, although I get a chance to see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, I'd go on the road for two, three weeks, then come home for two, three weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that was better than San Francisco, because I wouldn't see him at all there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I decided to quit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here Buffalo, in the meantime, traded me off to Portland, Oregon.
[SPEAKER_00]: My old teammate Marvin Owen was managing the ball club over there, and I still got my last contract in the drawer.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I got my release about 10 years after that, before I got my release.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, uh, that was the extent of my baseball career as far as professional ball was concerned.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who, uh, you broke in with the, uh, or when you went down to, to, uh, Wichita, Longview.
[SPEAKER_00]: Longview, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager down in Longview?
[SPEAKER_00]: Uh, Hank Severide, the old St. Louis Brown catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Henry Severide, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: In all your, you played in how many different managers?
[SPEAKER_00]: I played, uh, well, stop and think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bruno Betzel was in Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: Quincy O'Neill was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall his name right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then I went to Hank Sever in the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I went back to the Texas League when the St. Louis Browns bought me Hornsby.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was under Hornsby for three years.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was Hornsby like as a manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: As a manager, he was hard to play ball for.
[SPEAKER_00]: He thought everybody was as good a hitter as he was, you know, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd have you take your strikes.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, when you take strikes in the big leagues, you've got to be a pretty good hitter because them pitchers, they get ahead of you.
[SPEAKER_00]: They can go to work on you, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And most good hitters, they don't take strikes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They take them three swings, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll never forget, especially when we're behind, you always have to take a strike, you know, once you get a base on ball or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll never forget, a rookie come up, and he told the kid to take the first strike, you know, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So the kid goes up there, he said, well, in other words, he said, take one, you know, take one.
[SPEAKER_00]: That meant take the first strike.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the kid went up there, he swung it the first one, he followed it off.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he took the next two right down the middle, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So he says, how come you didn't swing to those two?
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, well, you told me to take one.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, so I took two.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he didn't stay long.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was gone.
[SPEAKER_00]: After Hank Samarud, like I say, I played in the Army for three years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I went back to the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there's an old-time catcher there, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to play with the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall his name right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Taylor, Zach Taylor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Zach Taylor, old Zach Taylor was a catcher there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He still caught for us, you know, once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then from there I went to St. Paul and Dave...
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall his name.
[SPEAKER_00]: But from there I went to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Chicago was Jimmy Dykes.
[SPEAKER_00]: How's he like Jimmy Dykes?
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim Dykes?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, entirely different.
[SPEAKER_00]: What technique did he use?
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's Hornsby, the difference between Hornsby and him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby, as soon as he got in the clubhouse, he was under tension.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't smoke, you couldn't read newspapers, you couldn't do nothing when you got in that clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: You never lost a ball in a clubhouse, never lost a ball game in a clubhouse, but you was under tension at all times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dykes,
[SPEAKER_00]: Luke Atherton would come in every day and go to his office and tell them, I don't think I can make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think I can make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why they call them aches and pains.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think I'll be able to play today.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, and Dyke says to him, he says, you know, Luke, he says, someday, he says, you're really going to be sick.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, nobody's going to believe you, and you're going to die.
[SPEAKER_00]: You always come in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you play cards and relax all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He smoked a few cigars, probably.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, all the time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Him and the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not the ball pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted Lyons, all the time sparring around, you know, half-dressed, you know, sparring around, knocking cigars out of one another's mouths.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a lot of fun.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on the field, that's a horse of another color.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was business.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was all strictly business.
[SPEAKER_01]: You think Dykes' method was best?
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought so, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was more relaxed.
[SPEAKER_00]: He managed longer in horseback.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes, he did, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went from place to place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe great ballplayers don't make good men.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe they don't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because they're so good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, you know, Rog liked to play the horses, too, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometimes you'd see him in the morning, he wouldn't even speak to you, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: Like his mind was a blank or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: We always said that's when he lost, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when he was a lot of fun, well, that seems like that's when he won.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd he get away with this?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to bet money for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Spring Franklin was in West Palm Beach, he'd give me the money and I'd go bet on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd bet a hundred bucks, I'd bet a buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: But some of his horses come in second and third, he's always betting them on the nose.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd bet a dollar across the board.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that was his hobby, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, that kept him broke, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: But on the ball field, he was rough.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of your teammates with the Browns?
[SPEAKER_00]: With the Browns?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Harlan Cliff was one of them, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Sammy West was another one.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played center field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Hobo Hemsley, if you recall, Raleigh Hemsley, he was our catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me a little bit about Hemsley, his private life.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, he was a character.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and I,
[SPEAKER_00]: Went to Philadelphia, we were in Philadelphia, and went out for the evening, we had a few beers, we went different places.
[SPEAKER_00]: We come home about quarter to twelve, they were checking us in, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next morning I get up and read the paper for breakfast at nine o'clock, and here's Henry's in jail.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, how did they get in jail?
[SPEAKER_00]: He went, he come home with me, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he got out that night, he went out the back fire escape there somewhere, got out, went and got himself a rental car or something, and he didn't have a Pennsylvania driver's license, didn't have no driver's license at all I guess,
[SPEAKER_00]: He got himself jacked up a little bit, I guess, and he got into a spot where there was a bunch of Navy boys, and they worked him over a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I still don't know how he got out, but he got out.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's how he told me he got out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the times that he caught, I couldn't understand how he caught.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, well, by the third or fourth, he'd sweat out, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, it was all day ball in those days, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I never saw the man drunk myself, to tell you the truth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you say checked in?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a bed check?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yes, at midnight.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was this?
[SPEAKER_01]: With the Browns?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, with the St. Louis Browns, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Barnsby do this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, all big leagues had that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, later on you had lights, you know, and under the lights you had two o'clock, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody didn't have lights in those days.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did Dykes have a bed check?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, you had a bed check at twelve o'clock.
[SPEAKER_00]: At two o'clock at night game, you played knifeball, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You played two o'clock.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember
[SPEAKER_00]: Texas League, we played Fort Worth with a double hitter, and it's supposed to be 9 and 7, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So we started out with 17 and 10, 2-10 in the morning when we finished up with a double hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Tony Kubik's father, you remember Tony Kubik?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Tony Kubik's father, he was Milwaukee, and Jack Cloza, they joined us that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Cloza had two triples, only two hits a got, about 13, 14 times at bat, and both of them won the ball game, I'll never forget that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I played ball with Tony Kubik's dad.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, his name was Tony, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he played ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never got in the big leagues, but he played, well, his home was Milwaukee, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim Levy with you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Jim was there ahead of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim was there ahead of me, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Sammy West.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we had Moose Saunders.
[SPEAKER_00]: Moose Saunders is blind now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess somebody says outside of Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a big boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sammy West.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a boy out of Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall his name.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a great big sign in
[SPEAKER_00]: Wright Field and Swartzman-Spark, and he wasn't too graceful as an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Yankees had the bases full, and out of your color, you hit a dick, you somehow hit a fly ball, and he charged in on it, and he overran it, and he started backing up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was backing up faster than he was coming in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on that sign, Wright Field, it was a schick sign, a man was shaving his face, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he hit, you could hear it all over the ballpark when he backed into that wall, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So the ball, that's the first time I ever seen Hornsby laugh.
[SPEAKER_00]: with their bases full, two outs, everybody's running.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he didn't get the ball, had the ball come back to the infield, and he come in, he got the ball, he's throwing the base runner out at third base, he threw the ball on a flyer into the dugout where Harvey was sitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Husband took off, you know, he went in the tunnel down there, and he come back out laughing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, what the hell, what's gonna happen next, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: And after we got the side out, we talked to Bruce, Bruce Camp, Bruce Camp.
[SPEAKER_00]: The following year, he had something happen to his body.
[SPEAKER_00]: Something happened to his body and he come back, he was voted the most clear of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, he asked Bruce, do you hurt yourself?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, no, I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took his cap off and run his hand through his hair, come up with a handful of blood.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll be a son of a gun.
[SPEAKER_00]: That razor must have nicked me, he says.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Bruce Campbell said that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those are the things you can't forget, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was the funniest thing ever?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that ranked among them?
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it's funny, you know, when you're stealing third base, when a man on third base is very funny, but it's funny when you get up there and look at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did that once.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've seen it happen several times.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've seen...
[SPEAKER_00]: Describe this again.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you're on second base, you hit the ground ball, and he's on second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: And maybe the shortstop at third base, whoever feels the ball throws it away at first, you go from home plate all the way to second, then he goes from second base to third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Unknowingly, you know, the guy, the pitcher goes into a wind-up, you know, and what's he doing winding up?
[SPEAKER_00]: So you're taking off, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: But you don't know the guy's on third.
[SPEAKER_00]: You figure, geez, if I can go from home to second, he should go from second to home when the ball's thrown in the right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he probably, after the ball was fielded, he probably went back to second, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thinking they're going to, you know, pick him off or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And by the time he gets going to find out the ball is thrown in the right field, he can't go any further in the center.
[SPEAKER_00]: But here I'm running and I thought the guy scored, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: As the pitcher goes into his lineup and I'm taking off and what's he lining up for, I'm taking off.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that only happens once, you know, that's how you learn.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've seen it happen several times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hard to say about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, get out of here for making mistakes, mental mistakes more for the mechanical, you know what I mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you do the wrong thing, like you run on a fly ball, you say, what you doing running on a fly ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought it was two outs.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't think, I'll do the thinking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because by errors like this, we drop the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the only, anybody that played the game knows he dropped balls, or he threw balls away, or he kicked balls away.
[SPEAKER_00]: But mental error, that means your mind isn't on the game or something, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I seen two guys, that was the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bo Bell was one.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Tony, I don't know what his name was, I can't recall, but they was playing for Galveston.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with San Antonio then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I can't recall this guy's, oh, Pit Purdy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pit Purdy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was quite a ball player for, for Beloit.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with somebody too for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Played big league, but this was on his way down.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he played with Beloit Wisconsin College against, against Notre Dame.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was quite a drop kicker in the 20s.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, someone was in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Pitt hit the ball, right drive to center field, between center and right, rather, and these two guys ran into one another and they knocked both, they knocked themselves out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tony Governor and Bobel, that's what, Tony Governor played center field and Bobel played right from there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was 19, 1933, 32, somewhere in there, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he got a home run because his ball landed before the second baseman around got the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitt ran all the way around.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the most sorriest thing I ever saw because they carried them both off on stretchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of the funny things, you have to stop and think some of the funny things that have happened, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, old ball players talking, you used to hear some of the craziest stories.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's the truth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wonderful.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: It must be a...
[SPEAKER_00]: It was quite a career.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I say, we didn't make much money in them days because...
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, the guys in the shop didn't make much money either.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, I was during the Depression when I started.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 29, you know, 30 and 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I always made it, managed to make it go.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't have to get into no bread lines like a lot of guys did, you know, working in the shop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a favorite pitcher to hit against in the big ten?
[SPEAKER_00]: Whoo!
[SPEAKER_00]: Not hardly a favorite, but I liked to be bad against left-handers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked to be bad against left-handers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was the first guy that Robert Feller ever faced in 1936 in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's a good game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, no, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he first come from Des Moines or somebody had him, that's when they had that little controversy, who owns him?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I guess Cleveland had to pay so much money to get him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was lost then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget, well he had a man on first base and second base, and he looked the man up.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, there was five runs behind or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a good time to, you know, break a rookie in, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they put him in, put Bob in, and the guy they took out was Pat Malone.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with you guys for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1936 I guess it was, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well he was with us for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well Pat, they took Pat out, and they put Rapid Robert in, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just looked at the base on the back, you know, at second base and fired.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he missed the catcher, missed me, hit the grandstand.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the grandstand just shook.
[SPEAKER_00]: Man, to that guy's throat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next boy does the same thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I managed to get a base on balls off of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether to sway, duck, or what to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the first time he started against us, I'll never forget, that was in Cleveland, maybe a month or two later.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he struck out 16 of us, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got everybody but Harlan Clift.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Harlan Clift made some kind of remarks in the newspapers, you know, about the sports rather.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get everybody, but he didn't get three.
[SPEAKER_00]: So next time he started again, he says he got Harlan Clift three different times.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't really get that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't say much after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he didn't say much.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was terrific.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know when I went out in 1939, we was in the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: A guy could really hit Robert.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Robert, I read stories where Robert was himself in the Rip Radcliffe because he slapped at the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just slapped at the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't swing, he slapped.
[SPEAKER_00]: The harder you swung, the harder it was to hit him, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd just slap at that ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he hit him pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Dykstra would say, don't swing at his curveball, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, his curveball was as fast as his fastball, and it dropped, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when he come back, I thought it was his fastball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: It got so far and all of a sudden it left.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't a slow roundhouse like some guys do, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was like a fastball and just down the side.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was terrific.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was your best pitcher at the Browns?
[SPEAKER_00]: Best pitcher?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Bobo Newsom was our best pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you remember Bobo?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bobo.
[SPEAKER_00]: All kinds of stories about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bobo, he's a dandy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you a story about Hemsley again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, well, Bobo, I'll tell you this one about, in Detroit, we could get beer, go through the restaurant, if you, you know, Hardincliffe and I always signed, one day we'd have a bottle of beer a piece, you know, and we'd sign it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it's like a check, you know, so we wouldn't pay for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The bellhop would bring it up, we'd sign it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, the ball club wasn't supposed to pick it up, but they would pick it up, because in Detroit, at the Book Cadillac, it was going through the kitchen as part of the meal, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Otherwise, when you had your clothes clean, so you hadn't washed or anything like that, there was all extras.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, all extras.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you took care, when you was checking out of the hotel, you'd go to the desk and ask for your extras.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we had two bottles one day, two bottles the next day, you know, and there was no extras, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we'd go to bed at night, right above us, there was, you know, about 11 o'clock, there was noise going on, you know, we looked up and there was Hemsley and Buck and those guys having a lot of fun up there, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were bringing it up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was about a half a dozen guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were bringing it up there by the case.
[SPEAKER_00]: See?
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were signing for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So at that time, it was $12, two bits a bottle.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about $12 a case, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: $6 a case.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, two bits a bottle.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what they were, two bits a bottle.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we always stay down to our two.
[SPEAKER_00]: But these guys get down to a case.
[SPEAKER_00]: So one day, Hornsby had a meeting, and he says, Hemsley and Mr. Newsome, he says, we don't mind paying for your food, he says, but if you're gonna bring guests to the hotel and feed them, expect the ball club to pay for them, he says, I don't think that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, you guys, well, he was allowed the four and a half or five bucks a day then, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: And these guys were eating eight and nine dollars a day, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: Six dollars was beer.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Hornsby never did find out, and he just told them to cut it out, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: If you bring a friend in, you pay for his meal.
[SPEAKER_00]: The club shouldn't pay for his meal.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there weren't meals, there was just beer.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd sign one day, the other guy signed the other day.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were here, we were just getting a bottle of beer, and these guys were getting by the case, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: You call him Mr. Hensley, Mr.?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Buck, or whatever it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Buck?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Buck, or Al Bobo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he had, he had some good days.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know he had, always behind a rule one time, if you had two stripes on a batter,
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd hit a two-nothing pitch and get a base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cost you 25 bucks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, 25 bucks didn't mean a lot of money to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Buck Newsome had two strikes on the guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sort of high outside pitch, and this guy reaches out for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't a good pitch, but he reached out and slapped it into right field for a base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cost Buck 25 bucks.
[SPEAKER_00]: So every time Buck got ahead of a man, two strikes and no balls, he'd hit the gravestone where there was nobody on base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd make sure he wasn't going to hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, you know, you can pitch a ball, a bad ball, a guy still can reach out and reach, hit it, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Be lucky enough to get a base hit and cost you 25 bucks.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that's how lucky he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was strict as a dickens.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about, was Blayholder still with you?
[SPEAKER_00]: George was with us, George.
[SPEAKER_00]: Blayholder was one of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of our pitchers, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, slow going, slow, he's from the South.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was he like?
[SPEAKER_00]: He, George, oh, he was happy-go-lucky.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just, he was like a loner.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we had another guy, I can't think of his name, but he was heavy drinker.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Harvey would always say, if you want a drink, he says, drink in your room.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, don't go out where the public can see you, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, you want to go drink because you had a bad day?
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, go out by yourself because nobody knows you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Don't go out with your friend you think is your friend.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he's the first, he's the first guy calls the front office the following day, says he was out with you, he was out with you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he does the complaining, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which has been since.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there much drinking in your time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it wasn't, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not excessive, but I mean, some guys would.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had one or two on a club with Bobby Overduke.
[SPEAKER_00]: because there's nothing wrong with having a drink.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean a beer, especially because I didn't drink the booze, I just drank beer myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: But some of these guys would drink that stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a bad day, probably like what they say, when it drowns your sorrows, I guess, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, no, that wasn't... You never went to the ballpark that way any other time?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, no, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never saw any of them come out that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not to the ballpark, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you go to work during 29, 30, and 31, I was playing, that was prohibition, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was no drinking at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, you get a bottle of homebrew somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: You always find out you get a bottle of homebrew, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we used to go, when I was at Quincy in the Three-Eyed League, my brother was over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come pay me a visit, and we used to go across into, this guy, he wrote a story about the guy on a fence, what was his name?
[SPEAKER_00]: Tom Sawyer, yeah, what was the name of that little town?
[SPEAKER_00]: Cow, that's right, right across the river, Hannibal, Missouri, right across the river from Quincy.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to go to Hannibal and get a couple bottles of beer after it was, after the ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd ride a ferry across, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, I learned that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't do too much drinking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Burns?
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Burns was the first baseman, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: He remembered that name better than I do, guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm trying to say, he was from Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: What about him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was, well, he was a quiet guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a boy, but I had my girl at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was a good first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack was a good hustler too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Hemsley again now in St. Louis, he dressed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: The reason they called him hobo though, the way I understand, he had a brand new suit of clothes on.
[SPEAKER_00]: By the time he'd come back, he looked like a bum.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what he'd do with himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hobo, that's why they called him hobo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you hear?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, that's hobo.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one time he had a
[SPEAKER_00]: A brand new car, and I don't know, a post or something got in his way, and his daughter told my daughter a telephone post got in my daddy's way.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why he hit the post.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody got in his way.
[SPEAKER_00]: But yeah, that's how they call him Homer.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd be dressed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next day, the suit wouldn't look the same.
[SPEAKER_01]: Another name I was always fascinated by was Storty.
[SPEAKER_00]: Storty.
[SPEAKER_01]: Glenn Storty.
[SPEAKER_01]: Glenn, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was there before me, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Storty was before me, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess Levy and Starry were... Yeah, they were there about the time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Levy played football, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I can't recall him playing football, but he went to school somewheres, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what school he went to.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, that was quite a town, St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about some of these fellas up in St. Paul?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, George Washington, well, he played with the White Sox and he could swick that bat pretty good, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, they had a little
[SPEAKER_00]: fence along the right field foul line, around the dugout, where the people in the box seat, they're always lifted up, maybe about a foot and a half high, because he had a tendency to let go of the bat and always wind up in the box seats.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, Mr. Schultz called me about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, do you remember that little fence they used to raise up every time George come to bat?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I certainly do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Every time you come to bat, because a lot of bats got away on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took a swish.
[SPEAKER_00]: What ballpark was that in St. Paul?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was old Lexington, Lexington ballpark in Lexington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that a very good park?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, it was 320-something to the right, the left field, they had a skating rink.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was like a pavilion.
[SPEAKER_00]: About 350, 360 left center, 370-something in right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where was the skating rink?
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a skating rink and a roller rink, too, in left center field in Lexington Park, in St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was kind of an amusement park?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, no, no, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was just, that was a boundary line, I guess, as far as they could go.
[SPEAKER_00]: That pavilion probably was there before the ballpark or vice versa.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's as far as they could go.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you hit them on top of the pavilion.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted Williams was in Minneapolis when I was playing ball there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was there either way.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if you remember Nicollet Park in Minneapolis, that was 270 feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first time I went over there, Hump Pierce, Hump Pierce, he was our trainer.
[SPEAKER_00]: September already, somebody must have been practicing football out there, see, because they had heavy gear in the lockers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, what's this heavy gear doing in the lockers?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, Ollie used to use that in the right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would play in the right field today.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he took me out and showed me why.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, you know, every time somebody has a line drive, you turn around and you got concrete, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So you beat your brains out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't believe that sucker because he was 22, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I mean, you could see it was logical.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there was only 270 feet, about a 40-foot screen on there, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had nine, they had nine left-hand hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: Donnie Bush was married in 1929 over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nine left-hand hitters in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: All they had to hit without a fist was a two-base hit off that screen, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like Joe, Joe Hauser hit a lot of homers because of that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Sixty, oh I imagine, but Joe was pretty good hitter too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe hit sixty, Joe and I was the bankers, old-timers bankers in Milwaukee, last November I believe it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we was, a couple of big leaguers were hosts over there, we sat at the main table.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he only hit 69, I believe, over there in one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to, I was just a kid reading the sporting news in those days, and I was just amazed at all those home runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he hit 69.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I mean, now, you know, Ted Williams, he didn't amount to any ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't hit that many over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But some of them that he hit was across the street or over across the buildings and everything else over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But yet, you think the way he could switch that bat, of course, he hit all three of those too.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he only hit 40-something that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with Philadelphia, wasn't he, somewhere?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to say, what's Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I remember correctly.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe his fielding or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember Joe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he could.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that was, that's, he was a guy who was being honored.
[SPEAKER_00]: That day that we were there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was being honored that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was intrigued by that name.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was in Cleveland for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was the guy that the old-timers, the old-timers association honored.
[SPEAKER_00]: What do you do with that old-timers thing, brother?
[SPEAKER_00]: That invitation?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll have to send it over there now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just received a letter in the mail.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got 5,000 members.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they take in Sarah Crowes too, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's connected to the old ball player?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah, it could be.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it could be Bobby Brothers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's what they have over there, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there for the first time with that, and I introduced myself after the meeting was over, and they gave me help because I should have introduced myself before that, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So then they invited me to this, they have a banquet.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a chimney with the boys, you see?
[SPEAKER_00]: If you got your $2 dues paid up, you get all the beer all to eat you want for nothing, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then later on it was $12.50 for a ticket.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they had a VIP room, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's Joe Kruger, president, Bill Lazarus, the secretary.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they got Hank Aaron and they got a whole list full of big league names that's on the board of directors, you know, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they usually have this at the
[SPEAKER_01]: What did they call you, Ollie?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Mr. Aloysius.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever call that at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: In school or anything?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: They called me Ollo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ollo, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ollo, I didn't know how to spell Ollo.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they changed it to Ollie.
[SPEAKER_01]: When was this, in school?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, in school, running around here in the fields.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody could spell Aloysius anyway, them days.
[SPEAKER_01]: Al Simmons had one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Al Simmons, he had that name too, but they called him Al.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went down to Ollie.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Chet Labs and all them guys come from Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got quite an organization.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's really something.
[SPEAKER_01]: His labs are up there now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wow, they go to Milwaukee, shouldn't they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: You get a lot of them there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Al Simmons, he's dead.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a book.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a book out over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: For the minor league ball players.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the program.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't think I could find it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You didn't get any more copies of this, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I got two of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just figured I'd ask you right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They honor the old timers.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, this is the guy that's sitting at the main table.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's Halsey Hall who was over there from Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's what they call him, Unser Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder what that's for, our Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know, I'm sure of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would be uncle.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, it's in German.
[SPEAKER_01]: Unser, yes, that's our Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Say Joe in German, I guess it's Joe.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right, Joe, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bruce Fleming.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's playing ball with Milwaukee now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've really gone big with that over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's your board of directors, look at this.
[SPEAKER_01]: They hang Aaron on here, see him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Tony Kuback Jr.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a really good year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you have a spare copy of this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Hey, thanks very much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you switch that tape?
[SPEAKER_00]: Look at this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Staten Island Baseball, south side of Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's, you got Chet, you got Chet Labner, there's Kenny Calverner.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kenny was at the banquet.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have to get a copy of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wonder who puts this out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got it over there from the old-timers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's, I'll show you about Al Simmons.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why don't you write to the old-timers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they'll probably get you.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's 1920s, see it?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: Merchandelle.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Merchants All.
[SPEAKER_00]: These are probably sponsors.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Winner.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dips.
[SPEAKER_00]: Larry Dips.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here it goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: At Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_00]: Doesn't say when he died.
[SPEAKER_00]: Doesn't say that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, May 26, 1956, four days after his 54th birthday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, 1956 is 18 years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would be 72 now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Four days after his 54th birthday.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's Connie Maxxie.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dedication Day.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's an old ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was going to say, there's an old man with an old ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's one out of hell.
[SPEAKER_00]: L. Simmons Field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know him pretty well?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't know L too well, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now here's what L looked like when he was playing summer from 1920.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they got Shet Labs in here too someplace.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a little bit later than you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Labs has a tremendous minor leaguer, never did much in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not too much, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me just adjust that one this time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah, just to... Yeah, ask him to send you one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we had more fun playing, I think, them days than we have now, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just like this man over, just like Charlie Schultz over the, over the telephone, he says, Ali, he says, they took the game away from the people, he says.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now they build these huge stadiums, he says, and you sit two blocks away from it and you watch the action, he says, it's not like it was in St. Paul, you know, you could touch the ball players, everybody was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever play in Rutberg Stadium in Columbus?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, I mean, I played Redbird Stadium in Columbus, Ohio, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that was, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played, well, they got one in Rochester, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: What do they call that, Cardinal, or?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think it's Red Wing Stadium.
[SPEAKER_01]: Red Wing, yeah, yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Silver Stadium now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah, Columbus, sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we've seen a lot of ball games.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played in the old ballpark there, too, in 1929, when I first started out.
[SPEAKER_00]: What kind of a ballpark?
[SPEAKER_00]: Neal's Park.
[SPEAKER_00]: Neal's Field, yeah, Neal's Park, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think there was a prisoner, an Ohio State prisoner was behind it or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could see the guards walking along.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the only time I played it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was 1929.
[SPEAKER_00]: Once or twice I went in it, because I joined them in June.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think we made one trip through there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Neal's.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it wasn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: That new one was great.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was real nice.
[SPEAKER_00]: The real nice ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that Jet Stadium?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's Jet Stadium.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, and it's so sad now.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Cardinals sold it in 54, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they transferred to Omaha, their franchise.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's nobody in Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the people in Columbus, the Columbus Civic Group bought it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was municipally owned and operated for about 15 or 16 more years.
[SPEAKER_01]: They renamed the club the Jets, and the team, the state of the Jet State.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then in 69, they just gave up.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were losing so much time.
[SPEAKER_01]: They transferred to Charles in West Virginia, which is about 80 miles from us, and we go down there a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's an association or international?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's international.
[SPEAKER_00]: International, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jet Stadium has just gone to sea.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just gone to sea.
[SPEAKER_01]: Beautiful ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever play in Charleston, West Virginia?
[SPEAKER_01]: Exhibition game.
[SPEAKER_01]: What ballpark was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Geez, I wouldn't want to call it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Senator Fieldhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: Senator Fieldhouse was coming through there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought there was, where's that?
[SPEAKER_01]: What?
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought Wattpaw Park was going.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wattpaw Park was built in 1947, so you wouldn't have played there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a nice little ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not to know it, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: His name was Powell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Powell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not Jake.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not like Jake.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know Jake?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell us some stories about Jake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I played against Jake, but I heard about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's all I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw him get a seizure on the league park there in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a caramel field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was a character.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was a character.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, all you know is what you read in the paper.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't want to say, oh, I got in trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: swinging bats at some of these guys, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had some characters.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the, uh, well, name some more characters.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see, uh, well, uh, Lloyd Brown, you remember Lloyd Brown, he was a Cleveland
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was in St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was no character, but he was in St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Swift, he played with me in St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in Pittsburgh, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went through it in his career.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was in the Three-Eyed League, too, one time when he was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: St. Greenberg and those guys, he's coming through at the same time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gary Walker one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's leading the league, I guess, around July 4th.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he had 50-some stolen bases.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was stealing the bass against us.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was second or third.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he was stealing third bass.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were way ahead.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't playing against us.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I remember reading the paper where somebody stole the bass and he was stealing another bass.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it didn't mean nothing, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he broke his leg.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was Hub, not Gerald.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Hub Walker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He broke his leg.
[SPEAKER_01]: Them guys could steal basses.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jerry Walker stealing a base and swallowing a plug of tobacco between the bases and practically strangling on the baseline there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You probably heard this story about why does it take a runner longer to go from second and third dust from first to second?
[SPEAKER_00]: The bases are 90 feet apart, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it takes a runner longer to go from second and third dust from first to second.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you know why?
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a short stop in between second and third.
[SPEAKER_01]: What are those Walker boys like?
[SPEAKER_00]: There were, there was, there was all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Hub was on the quiet side.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jerry was more aggressive.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know Jerry in, in Detroit one time, bases full, two outs, three and two.
[SPEAKER_00]: He bunted on our pitcher and got away with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now who in the world looking for a bunt three and two, two outs?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's bunt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody was running with the pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Made a good bunt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course he could have followed it off, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's the kind of guy he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was always doing unexpected.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I'll be with that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, I mean, uh, Gerald was more aggressive than Hubby.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't know him real well.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had the pleasure of playing against that one year in 1934.
[SPEAKER_00]: After that, he went to Boston, I guess, in 35 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, I bet you got a lot of stories from Stanley, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's very sharp.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so is she.
[SPEAKER_00]: 82, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's his second wife, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think that's his wife's sister, I believe.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's what she told us.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think that's what it is, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he came here in 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what, 46 years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Won't your wife come in and talk?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, come on, Clarence.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to get her, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's got some good stories.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what I said.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought we had chased her out.
[SPEAKER_02]: She doesn't want him on tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hi.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hello.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're going to have to give me your names again though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Murdoch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Murdoch, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is my wife, Clare.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm Peg Weardock.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hi.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I thought we chased you out of here when we came.
[SPEAKER_03]: I usually stay in the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_03]: You want to find out when you got married, what it was like being there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got married in 28.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's where I usually live, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you travel around much with your husband when he was playing ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just wherever he played.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go on the road at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just once.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that a lot of fun?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it's no fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll guarantee you that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now it would be a lot of fun, I imagine.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I mean, the children are grown up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, now, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: When they were small.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell them you never called me daddy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why always?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, they never called you by your name.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never called you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because if I had a bad day, you don't have to pick on her, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, I never sat in the, I always sat in the stands with children wrestling fans.
[SPEAKER_03]: And if he was up to bat, boy, they never said daddy.
[SPEAKER_03]: They always said Ollie.
[SPEAKER_03]: Isn't that funny?
[SPEAKER_02]: Mrs. Kobuleski never sat.
[SPEAKER_02]: She always sat in the stands, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I never sat.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, she didn't want to be with the wives.
[SPEAKER_02]: She told me that.
[SPEAKER_03]: With the children, with the children, it was safer to sit.
[SPEAKER_03]: There wasn't a box seat, because you never know when there'd be a foul.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then first thing you know, the children are playing.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're not sitting there and watching the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I had hands full.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get nervous when your husband was batting?
[SPEAKER_03]: Not very much.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sometimes I'd always sit there and listen to where everybody's talking.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that bother you?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I just sat there and I said, if you'd only know who's sitting over here listening to it.
[SPEAKER_03]: You wouldn't be saying those things.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob, you haven't heard the stands at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to go to a tavern after a ball game in St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went there about half the season, more than half the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: More than half the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: And nobody knew us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody knew us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I told you, it's best to go where nobody knows you can have a couple, three glasses of beer with your family and just go home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or otherwise, there's always somebody who wants to buy you one.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, buy you one, buy you one, buy you one.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the guy who's going to be the first one to call up the following day, you know, bragging he was out with you and got you drunk.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we were sitting there, we was in the playhouse, what do you think?
[SPEAKER_00]: One time when this guy at the, well, they always paid $0.15 at two places for a taxi or whatever.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this guy at the pass gate comes in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, hello Mrs. Bayman, how are you?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was eight or ten people down there, and we got eight or ten beers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody ever bought us a drink.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're all summer long, until this one night.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they all come over and talk to us.
[SPEAKER_00]: They all start buying us drinks.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was the last time I was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd sit there.
[SPEAKER_03]: We could have enjoyed it, because the girls at that time, they understand.
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd sit in the booth, and they would talk about him and about the ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_03]: The guys after the game, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they'd send Eddie to talk about it off the booth.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we'd say, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we'd just real quiet, and we'd be listening.
[SPEAKER_03]: So everything was all right until that one night.
[SPEAKER_03]: That one night came around, and I said, this is it.
[SPEAKER_03]: No more.
[SPEAKER_03]: After that, we never did go back.
[SPEAKER_03]: I did go with him to a dance.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was at the Big Wheel.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah, somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we were dancing.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we were dancing, and the first thing you know, I noticed the fellow recognized him.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they started talking.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I told him, I said, well, let's go.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we did, went to our table, finished our drink, and walked out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we sat in this place, that one tavern, where there's different comments after a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I say, one day you're a hero, next day you're a bum.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's what them guys do, lead the lead, the way they play tonight, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So you have a bad day.
[SPEAKER_00]: But same people, like I say, patch out and pack one day, and kick you in the butt the next, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have a pretty thick skin for that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, it is about me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was a sports writer.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, he said, I sat in the stands.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could hear him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never gave him no reason to give me that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I could hear what they talk about him and what they talk about all the ball players.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got scrapbooks over here.
[SPEAKER_03]: The way Ollie goes, that's the way the club goes.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know what?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was because I was doing good, you know what I'm saying?
[SPEAKER_03]: They never gave me going over to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had my own business.
[SPEAKER_00]: I kept my nose clean.
[SPEAKER_03]: How many children do you have?
[SPEAKER_00]: I have three.
[SPEAKER_03]: Two girls and...
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, the girls really did get the ones that really enjoyed the, just playing because the boy...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was three years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: He still remembers running around the bases in Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_03]: Are they married now?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he's in Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, the girls, yeah, I have 12 grandchildren.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, my.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play in an old orchestra?
[SPEAKER_01]: Off of it, off of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a man over here the other day, he sees a friend of mine over here, about a block away from the tavern, and he comes and sees him, see, and they both, one of them comes from Duluth and he comes from Buffalo here during the Depression and met here in South Bend one time on some kind of a job that was building a building or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: When it was tearing up bowling alleys, it was moving bowling alleys, that's what they were doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's how they met.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've been friends ever since, Waters Recreation.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about 150 years ago, they're both in the 70s now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we're just talking about Offerman Stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: It comes to you like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometimes you want to think you can't think of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next time it comes to you like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw a doubleheader there.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a nice ballpark there.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1946 Debris and Debris.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a nice ballpark, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Offerman Stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was the nicest park you played in, in minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_00]: In the minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Kansas City was a bad ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Indianapolis was a new ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Indianapolis was a nice ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that the one there now?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the one there now.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Downey Bushfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: The one I broke in on was on Washington Street, across the street from a streetcar barn over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the one I broke in in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I never played in this other one because I was gone in 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were still playing in the old one.
[SPEAKER_00]: This would come up about 32, 33 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Down in Bush is a newer one, is that it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, down in Bush is a new one, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's on the north side, north-west side of the channel.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other one was right straight down Washington Street, about maybe six blocks from the Marina.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that a pretty good park, or you're speaking of the newer one?
[SPEAKER_00]: The newer one.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, the other one was just a wooden ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first one was, yeah, just a wooden ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the little ballpark was a nice ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about the sportsman's park?
[SPEAKER_00]: In St. Louis?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that was an old ballpark down on the other side.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have no, they just had backstage, all of it, down the right field line, and down the left field line, and then the center field, right field, it was just nothing but bleachers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were the facilities very good there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, like locker room, showers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we used to go, as I said, crawl upstairs all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the new ones is real good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And by the way, I played in the old-timers game in 1967.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was my last ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Bloomington, Minnesota.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the old-time Saints play the old-time Minneapolis Millers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had Marty Stratton over there, after he shot his leg off.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he pitched bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the year I joined the White Sox in 39.
[SPEAKER_00]: He shot his leg off December 38, I believe it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was pitching bat in practice for a 39 season.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he come over there and played.
[SPEAKER_00]: Me and Art Herring played.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Tony, I mean, yeah, Giuliani, Tony Giuliani.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he's in some capacity with the Twins.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he's a coach or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he played because he used to play with the Saints.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had one guy there, 73 years old, played third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, don't hit the ball in third base because you might kill him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Oscar Rutger, he was playing first bass for us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oscar was there when Ben Chapman was there in 1929.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with the St. Paul Saints.
[SPEAKER_00]: He lives in St. Louis now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Williams played center field for us, because Williams at one time played for St. Paul.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boston was in town in 1967.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, Strzymski wasn't a player.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't get a chance to sing and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: But yeah, we had something like 29, 30,000 people.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we packed it in pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we only played three innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: I struck out the first time.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next time, I got a base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy after me got a base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I go from first to second.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the next guy bunting.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, it wasn't nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it was 10.
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy bunting the ball, and I'm running to third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm howling, third, third, third.
[SPEAKER_00]: The pitcher at the third base, and we're picking the ball up.
[SPEAKER_00]: They turn around and throw it to third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: They throw it to left field.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm running all the way home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Laughing like hell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why do you keep in such good shape?
[SPEAKER_01]: You're looking great.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just feel fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bowl.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bowl and play golf.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bought a bowl once a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was up to 202 pounds one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's after I quit smoking.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was about 180.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm 75 now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was 202 pounds.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, my God.
[SPEAKER_00]: So every Lent, I'm a Catholic.
[SPEAKER_00]: Every Lent come around, I quit drinking beer.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in six weeks time, I'm losing over 10, 12 pounds.
[SPEAKER_00]: And every Lent come around, I lose.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did that for about 15 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't do it this year.
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife said, you're skinny enough the way it is, why should you lose some more weight?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll probably lose about five pounds, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's how I come back down, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was 202 pounds when I seen that on a scale, I nearly died.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I played, my playing weight's more or less 165, 170, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then as I got older, I think I got up to 175.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any trouble getting in shape?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first year, I think I overdid it though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they sent me to, like I told you before, the Browns got a hold of me in 33.
[SPEAKER_00]: Birmingham bought me, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Southerly, that's where Dizzy Dean was with Houston.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget who was managing Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, Clyde.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stole all the bases for Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Clyde Milam, that's the guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he caught me sliding, you know, he said, boy, you don't slide that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went straight out, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I always have this to lose, like a hinge, you see, a little gear, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody taught you minor leagues how to slide, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he caught me doing that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I prefer going down there, because I couldn't stay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because at that time, you had to keep five, five rookies, I guess you had to keep, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if you was at bat in the association, which was higher than Southern Association, I was a triple A. I think I was at bat in 1929, something like 80 or 90 times.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he was as bad over 50 or 60, you was a regular, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why they couldn't take me as a rookie.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they wanted a pennant there the following year, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they liked me, but I mean, they couldn't keep me, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to carry five rookies.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, then I come back to Quincy.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 1932.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I had a good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when St. Louis Browns got me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sent me to Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: But all in all, it was quite an ordeal.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I say, it was in the...
[SPEAKER_00]: He had more fun playing ball, I think, than they have now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did you do in the off-season?
[SPEAKER_00]: The off-season?
[SPEAKER_00]: My brother and I opened up a tavern over here in 1935.
[SPEAKER_00]: We was in there until now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: You still have it?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Up until now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he got too old, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when I quit playing ball, I went to Studebaker's to work.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was at Studebaker's until they closed up here in 1963.
[SPEAKER_00]: After 63, I was playing politics a little bit, you know, and I got a job with the state as a driver examiner.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there for five or six years until they changed governors, you know, and you got kicked.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the governor got kicked out, you got kicked out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I did some favors for friends of mine.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did a hire for American Motors over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a plant, American Motors had a plant that was making army trucks, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I went down to the basement making little boxes, you know, for shipping and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was there for
[SPEAKER_00]: Practically four years, I get to be 65, 1965, and 1960 when I was 73, 74, no 72 I was 65 and I quit the 1st of 1973, I've been out since then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you do much hunting in Austria?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh I did, not no more, not no more, no, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I would keep a 4-5 o'clock every morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you go hunting with any of the other old timers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well I used to go with the old timers over here, we called the old timers Joe Baker, he was the violinist every once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stanley knows, well Stanley pitched to him too.
[SPEAKER_00]: But up until the last, now you've got too much hunting going on around here, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: Everything is being built in.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't want you to hunt here, they want you to hunt there, you can't hunt nowhere around here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although I did go one year for deer hunting up in Canada.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we didn't shoot no deer because the guy I was with, you had to get a deer at a certain time because he had to come back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in that woodhouse.
[SPEAKER_03]: Excuse me, that was your daughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which one?
[SPEAKER_03]: You were supposed to go watch your grandson.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, play ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's got a game at 5-3.
[SPEAKER_03]: Are they playing?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, they're having a... Are they playing?
[SPEAKER_03]: You listen to them?
[SPEAKER_03]: They don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: They...
[SPEAKER_03]: They're playing, I don't understand.
[SPEAKER_03]: This manager that... St. James?
[SPEAKER_03]: St. James is running around like mad looking for a diamond to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: Again?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, see, they're the umpires, the main ones.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's the one that just been said that they can't play.
[SPEAKER_00]: They can't play over there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Over there, it's Saturday.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How could he, what rights did he have to run around looking for diamonds?
[SPEAKER_03]: How about today?
[SPEAKER_03]: So they ran over there, and he's over there today, too, to see if that diamond is playable.
[SPEAKER_03]: Playable?
[SPEAKER_03]: Playable, if it is, he'll find it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was supposed to go see him play at 5, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: But as a rule, I bow on Monday nights, but today, the season's over, so I'm all done bowing.
[SPEAKER_03]: She's so rubber, she says she's not bowing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, when I get done eating, I'll go watch him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's 14.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's 14.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's eighth grade at the Christ the King.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wants to be a shortstop, but he can throw the ball pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, they make a picture out of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, if anybody can throw hard, they want to make a picture out of it, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they're fighting for the championship, and they're playing St. Cashmere's over here, oh, about a half a mile down the street.
[SPEAKER_00]: And these guys come from Roseland over here up north.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they're playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a chance to tie him or something, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wanted to play it Friday or Saturday.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wanted to play it Saturday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Saturday all day it rained over here.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was unplayable.
[SPEAKER_01]: And my son-in-law was taking the kids to bowl.
[SPEAKER_01]: They went to Bloomington, Indiana.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were in the end of the year.
[SPEAKER_01]: A bunch of kids from over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I belonged to Polish Falcons, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had 40 kids on a bus going there to bowl.
[SPEAKER_00]: Junior bowlers, you know, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's my son that took his boulders down there too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they wanted to play in the worst way, see, because they know he had to leave for Bloomington, and he wanted to get out because it was muddy, it was muddy.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they finally called off, he left at 1 o'clock instead of 2.
[SPEAKER_03]: You have any children, do you?
[SPEAKER_01]: We got two.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two boys, girls?
[SPEAKER_01]: Girl 19, boy 22.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's up at Hillsdale College, we're gonna pick her up in a couple of days.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Would you, could you sit on the couch for a moment for a picture of the two of you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, gee, I don't take good pictures at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'll catch you up.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't take good pictures at all.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't like to take pictures.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's why my grandchildren, they take pictures of me when I'm not working.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I still get kids who want autographs, you know, so I've got some pictures of a bust of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you have any spares?
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got a picture, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got a picture of myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to ask you, Mrs. Bayman, were you from South Bend yourself?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And where did you two meet?
[SPEAKER_03]: I have a sister married to his brother.
[SPEAKER_03]: Older brother.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sister's brother married to his brother.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's how we met.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stanley Kowalski marries his sister.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, his sister's, well, his first wife's sister.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, see, I wanted you to sign this.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: White Sox, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's a championship game.
[SPEAKER_01]: What's your first name?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jean.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jean, Jean.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, she said, Mr. Bates, this coach, he's such a, he's like, what I call him, a cutthroat.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's out there to win, and this grandson of mine is so mad, I said, gee, I says, Joanna, I hope he doesn't
[SPEAKER_03]: You see, so many buried and beaten, every one of us, and I hope not.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it's a poor sportsmanship, because he doesn't, the children see this and they hear everything he says, and it's not nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, you're welcome.
[SPEAKER_01]: Appreciate it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You want to see some trophies I got for going over there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I'd love that.
[SPEAKER_02]: You got that?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where I think we're keeping them for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're just talking ourselves.
[SPEAKER_02]: Women talk.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is not for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's like being on baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I told him that's talking.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm not going.
[SPEAKER_02]: But, well, that's what I do.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just, you know, I don't say, you know, let him carry on.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we had to go, he had to go to a convention up in London, Ontario.
[SPEAKER_02]: And since our daughter was almost ready to come home,
[SPEAKER_02]: He thought he'd go and teach some old ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_02]: We left there yesterday, and he'd teach some old ballplayers, and then we picked her up on Wednesday.
[SPEAKER_02]: How could you do that?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're just not very well organized here.
[SPEAKER_00]: What is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you have any cash to do?
[SPEAKER_02]: It's just our little old thing here.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is the Arts Association?